<resources>
    <string name="app_name">citeslist</string>
    <string name="cairo">Cairo</string>
    <string name="Giza">El_Giza</string>
    <string name="alexandria">Alexandria</string>
    <string name="luxor">luxor</string>
    <string name="aswan">Aswan</string>
    <string name="dahab">Dahab</string>
    <string name="gona">fayoum</string>
    <string name="Hurghada">El_Gharda</string>
    <string name="sharm">Sharm El_shaikh</string>
    <string name="marsaalam">Marsa Alam</string>
    <string name="matrouh">Marsa matrouh</string>
    <string name="swia">Siwa osais</string>
    <string name="fayoum">Fayoum</string>
    <string name="alamein">Alalmein</string>
    <string name="pyrmid">Pyrmids</string>
    <string name="book">book</string>
    <string name="alazher">Alazher park</string>
    <string name="thezoo">the zoo</string>
    <string name="sphinx">great sphinx</string>
    <string name="places">top places</string>
    <string name="citadel">citadel</string>
    <string name="egyptmusuem">egyption musuem</string>
    <string name="cairotower">cairo tower</string>
    <string name="asha">ashaFahmi palace</string>
    <string name="elmoez">elmoez street</string>
    <string name="nationeg">national musuem</string>
    <string name="abdeinpalace">abadein palace</string>
    <string name="khanelkhalili">khan elkhalili</string>
    <string name="elbaron">elbaron palace</string>
    <string name="citbey">citbey citadel</string>
    <string name="abuqir">Abu Qir</string>
    <string name="boltcastle">bolt Castle</string>
    <string name="lostcity">the Lost City</string>
    <string name="komeldikka">kom El_Dikka</string>
    <string name="raseltin">Ras El_tin Palace</string>
    <string name="alexlibrary">Alex Library</string>
    <string name="stanley">stanelt Bridge</string>
    <string name="abasmosque">Abas Mosque</string>
    <string name="montazh">EL_Montazh</string>
    <string name="alshabamosque">Alshaba Mosque</string>
    <string name="coloredcanyonsinai">colored canyon sinai</string>
    <string name="peaceicon">Peace Icon</string>
    <string name="sohosunset">soho sunset</string>
    <string name="mountcat">Mount catrein</string>
    <string name="dolphinpark">Dolphin Park</string>
    <string name="rasmohamed">"RasMohamed "</string>
    <string name="safri">Safri</string>
    <string name="sghazalagarden">GhazalaGarden</string>
    <string name="petrasightseeing">Petra Sightseeing</string>
    <string name="abosimple">Abo simple temple</string>
    <string name="alkarnk">Karanak Temple</string>
    <string name="kalabsha">Temple of kalabsha</string>
    <string name="komobo">Temple of komobo</string>
    <string name="ramses">Temple of Ramses</string>
    <string name="sohailisland">Sohail Island</string>
    <string name="valentin">Valentin Island</string>
    <string name="ajelicaisland">Ajelica Island</string>
    <string name="highdam">Highdam Bridge</string>
    <string name="abydoscity">Abydoscity</string>
    <string name="deirelmedina">Deir El_Medina</string>
    <string name="luxormusuem">Luxor Musuem</string>
    <string name="motuarytemple">MotuaryTemple</string>
    <string name="nadaland">Ndaland Park</string>
    <string name="bananaisland">Banana Island</string>
    <string name="vallyofking">Vallyofking</string>
    <string name="vallyofqueen">vallyofqueen</string>
    <string name="ramsuemtemple">RamsuemTemple</string>
    <string name="intergarden">InterGarden</string>
    <string name="luxorcorish">Luxor cournish</string>
    <string name="luxortemple">Luxor Temple</string>
    <string name="sahlhasheesh">Sahlhasheesh</string>
    <string name="magwishisland">MagwishIsland</string>
    <string name="jethonisland">jethonisland</string>
    <string name="sandmusuem">SandMusuem</string>
    <string name="aquirm">aquirm</string>
    <string name="grazyland">Grazyland</string>
    <string name="aldaybeach">Al_Daybeach</string>
    <string name="sandbadvillage">sandbadvillage</string>
    <string name="thrushtree">Thrush Tree</string>
    <string name="meteorlake">Meteor lake</string>
    <string name="abughosounwreck">Abughosoun Wreck</string>
    <string name="portghali">Port Ghali</string>
    <string name="berenicevillage">Berenice Village</string>
    <string name="alsamadayreserve">Alsamaday Reserve</string>
    <string name="wadielgemalreserve">WadielgemalReserve</string>
    <string name="dolphinhouse">Dolphin House</string>
    <string name="leadmountaun">Lead Mountain</string>
    <string name="saltlake">Salt Lake</string>
    <string name="theshali">TheShali</string>
    <string name="templeoftheoracl">TempleoftheOracl</string>
    <string name="sandsea">Great Sand Sea</string>
    <string name="fatnasisland">Fatnas Island</string>
    <string name="ghazala">Ghazala</string>

    <string name="mountain">deadMountain</string>
    <string name="housemusuem">HouseMusuem</string>
    <string name="djaracave">Djara Cave</string>
    <string name="aielgarden">Aiel Garden</string>
    <string name="nabaqreserve">Nabq Reserve</string>
    <string name="wadignai">WadiGnai</string>
    <string name="coloredcanyons">coloredcanyons</string>
    <string name="bluehole">BlueHole</string>
    <string name="lighthouse">LightHouse</string>
    <string name="canyon">canyon</string>
    <string name="lagonisland">LagonIsland</string>
    <string name="cleopatrabeach">cleopatrabeach</string>
    <string name="agiba">Agiba Beach</string>
    <string name="saltcave">SaltCve</string>
    <string name="rommel">RommelBeach</string>
    <string name="rommelcave">RommelCave</string>
    <string name="algharam">Algharam</string>
    <string name="ramses2">TempleOfRamses</string>
    <string name="generalreserve">Generalreserve</string>
    <string name="wadielrayen">WadielRayen</string>
    <string name="jabelmedwar">Jabel medwar</string>
    <string name="hawrapyrmid">Hawra Pyrmid</string>
    <string name="pyrmidofseila">pyrmidofseila</string>
    <string name="pyrmidofsenusret">pyrmidofsenusret</string>
    <string name="pyrmidofamemhat3">pyrmidofamemhatIII</string>


    <string name="cities">cities</string>
    <string name="trips">trips</string>
    <string name="offers">offers</string>
    <string name="reserve">reserve</string>
    <string name="location">location</string>
    <string name="aboutapp">aboutapp</string>
    <string name="about">about</string>
    <string name="username">username</string>
    <string name="Next">Next</string>
    <string name="Tickit">Tickt</string>
    <string name="Ticket">Tiket</string>
    <string name="Name">Name</string>
    <string name="Time">Time</string>
    <string name="Date">Date</string>
    <string name="To">To</string>
    <string name="From">From</string>
    <string name="Busnumber">Busnumber</string>
    <string name="print">please dont forget to print or screen this ticket because you cant enter without it</string>
    <string name="time">time</string>
    <string name="price">price</string>
    <string name="Add">Add</string>
    <string name="info">this application help you to get information about touristic places in egypt and book your trip</string>
    <string name="b1">This icon show cities and their touristic places in egypt</string>

    <string name="b">this icon show table of available trips of each city  </string>
    <string name="admins">admins</string>
    <string name="password">password</string>
    <string name="busnumber">busnumber</string>
    <string name="AddTrip">AddTrip</string>
    <string name="ShowTrips">ShoeTrips</string>
    <string name="UpDateTrip">UpDateTrip</string>
    <string name="contact">contact</string>
    <string name="DeletTrip">DeletTrip</string>
    <string name="DeleteTrip">DeleteTrip</string>
    <string name="OK">OK</string>
    <string name="wadihitan">WadiHitan</string>
    <string name="qarunqpalace">Qarunqpalace</string>
    <string name="comoshin">comoshin</string>
    <string name="kranis">kranis</string>
    <string name="tunisvillage">Tunis Village</string>
    <string name="artcenter">Art Center</string>
    <string name="citadel_des">The Citadel of Cairo or Citadel of Saladin
        (Arabic: قلعة صلاح الدين, romanized: Qalaʿat Salāḥ ad-Dīn)
        is a medieval Islamic-era fortification in Cairo, Egypt, built by Salah ad-Din (Saladin)
        and further developed by subsequent Egyptian rulers. It was the seat of government in Egypt
        and the residence of its rulers for nearly 700 years from the 13th to the 19th centuries.
        Its location on a promontory of the Mokattam hills near the center of Cairo commands a strategic
        position overlooking the city and dominating its skyline.
        At the time of its construction, it was among
        the most impressive and ambitious military fortification
        projects of its time.[1] It is now a preserved historic site, including mosques and museums.</string>
    <string name="egyptiannusuemdesc">The Egyptian Museum of Antiquities contains many important pieces of ancient Egyptian history. It houses the world\'s largest collection of Pharaonic antiquities. The Egyptian government established the museum built in 1835 near the Ezbekieh Garden and later moved to the Cairo Citadel. In 1855, Archduke Maximilian of Austria was given all of the artifacts by the Egyptian government; these are now in the Kunsthistorisches Museum, Vienna.

A new museum was established at Boulaq in 1858 in a former warehouse, following the foundation of the new Antiquities Department under the direction of Auguste Mariette. The building lay on the bank of the Nile River, and in 1878 it suffered significant damage owing to the flooding of the Nile River. In 1891, the collections were moved to a former royal palace, in the Giza district of Cairo.[1] They remained there until 1902 when they were moved again to the current museum in Tahrir Square, built by the Italian company of Giuseppe Garozzo and Francesco Zaffrani to a design by the French architect Marcel Dourgnon.[2]

In 2004, the museum appointed Wafaa El Saddik as the first female director general</string>
    <string name="cairotowerdesc">From its 187 meters, the Cairo tower offers the most amazing panoramic views of the Egyptian capital. It is advised to go up to the tower circular observation deck in the late morning or late afternoon for the clearest views of the city.

        You will also find a restaurant at the top of the tower.
        Occasionally, the restaurant revolves around the tower is main axis
        The tower was designed by the Egyptian architect, Naoum Chebib.
        Its completion took 5 years, from 1956 to 1961.
        Opening Hours: From 8 am to midnight. 
    </string>
    <string name="ashafamidesc">Designed by Italian architect Antonio Lasciac in a beautiful
        , classic European style, the palace was built in 1907 by the Nile River in Zamalek
        on an area of 2,700 square meters. he two-storey building contains five rooms with various
        original textile art and European oil paintings. A room originally used for playing billiards 
        and a billiards scoring board was turned into a living room, where the name of Fahmy  father has been 
        engraved in the wood. The furniture in the living room doesn’t belong to Fahmy, as the government and curators carefully
        chose the furniture to match the decorations in the room.</string>
    <string name="elmoezdesc">It is a 1 km long pedestrian street, and to quote the UN, 
        it has “the greatest concentration of medieval architectural treasures in the Islamic world”. 


It might not be the Pyramids, but it is a definite must-see to get a true feel for the history of Cairo as a city,
        and to see some frankly mind-blowing medieval Islamic architecture and art. And not in a stuffy, museum-type behind-the-glass environment
        -- it’s a free pedestrian street with the architecture all around you, so you don’t have to worry about paying money to stare at super curated things that you a) don’t really understand, and b)
        are kind of boring. One thing we can promise about Moez Street -- it is not boring, that’s for sure. 
</string>
    <string name="nationegdesc">The NMEC is the first of its kind in Egypt and the Arab world. It presents the full range of the richness and diversity of Egyptian civilization throughout the ages, from prehistoric times to the present day by focusing on its continuity and stability as demonstrated by its tangible and intangible heritage. The museum’s exceptional collection includes the royal mummies, which are exhibited in a new interactive display using 21st century cutting-edge technology to go beneath the wrappings and reveal their secrets, in addition to shedding light on the rituals and religious beliefs surrounding mummification in ancient Egypt.</string>
    <string name="abdeendesc">Abdeen Palace is a historic Cairo palace built as one of the official residences for the former ruling monarchy and royal family of Egypt. It is now one of the official residences and the principal workplace of the President of Egypt, located above Qasr el-Nil Street in eastern Downtown Cairo, Egypt</string>
    <string name="khanelkhalilidesc">Khan el-Khalili is a famous bazaar and souq in the historic center of Cairo, Egypt. Established as a center of trade in the Mamluk era and named for one of its several historic caravanserais, the bazaar district has since become one of Cairos main attractions for tourists and Egyptians alike</string>
    <string name="elbarondesc">The Baron Empain Palace, better known as Le Palais Hindou, is a distinctive and historic Hindu temple inspired mansion in Heliopolis, a suburb northeast of central Cairo, Egypt. It was founded by Edward Louis Joseph Empain, a Belgian businessman who was awarded the title of "Baron" by the King of Belgium.</string>
    <string name="saltlakedesc">Siwa has over 10 million palm tree, full of lakes . the nature combination of water /gold sand/greens/blue sky is beyond imagination. The most famous is the salt lake with its high percentage of salts and minerals. it is a relaxation ,healing shallow water where you can float.</string>
    <string name="theshalidesc">The village of Shali in Siwa Oasis - Matrouh Governorate. "Shali" is a Siwi word meaning city. The village of Shali was built from the material of the archive, which is clay saturated with salt. If it dries up, it becomes similar to cement in its hardness. It is a unique style of construction, and it dates back to the sixth century AH / twelfth century AD.
The city is surrounded by a sturdy building wall that has only one entrance called “The Bab Anshal”, meaning the gate of the City, and on the northern side of the city wall there is the ancient mosque, which is the oldest mosque built with mud in Africa, and after a century passed, a second gate was opened on the southern side of the wall near the oil press called “Bab Athrat”, meaning the new door and a third door opened after a century had passed, called “Qaduha” for women only.

</string>
    <string name="templeoforacledesc">is a spectacular, The temple of Amun, built during twenty-sixth Dynasty, the temple and its oracle flourished into the Greek and Roman times The temple was built on a top of mountains. The ruins of the temple can be reached by climbing a well-marked path up the side of the rock. According to a legend, the temple was built in honour of ham, the son of Noah, by Danaus the Egyptian, another legend relates the foundation of the temple to the Greek god Dionysus. While lost in the western desert. Dionysus was perishing of thirst, when A ram appeared and guided him to the spring of Agroumi, In Gratitude Dionysus erected this temple.
Oracle, Manifestations of God, were highly revered in the ancient world, Able to see into the future they were consulted regularly before important decisions were
made
</string>
    <string name="greatseadesc">The Great Sand Sea is an approximately 72,000 km² sand desert in the Sahara between western Egypt and eastern Libya in North Africa. Some 74% of the area is covered by sand dunes.</string>
    <string name="fatnasislanddesc">Located in Siwa, within 0.8 mi of Island On Lake and 1.4 mi of Island On Lake, Marassina Fatnas Island camp provides accommodations with a garden and as well as free private parking for guests who drive. The property is around 1.9 mi from Lake, 2.4 mi from Old fortress of Shali and 3.1 mi from Mountain Of The Dead. The property is 4.3 mi from Cleopatra Spring.
Featuring a private bathroom, rooms at the hostel also provide guests with a lake view.
Guests at Marassina Fatnas Island camp can enjoy a halal breakfast.
</string>
    <string name="ghazaladesc">No reservation costs. Great rates. Book at over 1,400,000 hotels online. No Booking Fees. 24/7 Customer Service. Best Price Guarantee. We speak your language. Read Real Guest Reviews. Get Instant Confirmation. Types: Hotels, Apartments, Villas, Hostels, Resorts.</string>
    <string name="deadmountaindesc">mountain contains number of tombs. The tombs, which cover every inch of its base and are situated on its terraces and on all sides of the conical part, date from the 26th dynasty , the Greek and the Roman periods, though there appear to be no Christian burials.


One of the most famous tombs is that of SiAmun which is considered the most beautiful one in the oasis of the Western desert. The tomb dates to about the 3rd century BC. It was discovered in October,1940 and unfortunately, some of its decorations were badly damaged by soldiers in Siwa at that time, who cut away parts of the painted plaster. The tomb, as with others in the area, was robbed during the Roman period.
</string>
    <string name="housemusuemdesc">The Museum at Siwa is an example of what the traditional house looks like in Siwa Oasis, Siwa House Museum also has a great collection of displays for daily-life tools and accessories used by Siwan people.
The Siwan house ceilings and doors are made of palm wood, and mud and olive leaves help strengthen the roof against the rain. Most of the houses in Siwa as we can see them during Egypt Tours have two floors and a rooftop terrace, where they sleep in the summer or sit in the evening for dinners and chats in the open air.
</string>
    <string name="djarcavedesc">The quiet and mystical desert, with its bedrock formations fighting the gravity, is interrupted by one of the most beautiful pre-historic sites in the western desert; Djara Cave . The cave contains the only rock-art depictions in a 250 km range, with perfectly preserved scenes of gazelles and other wild animals. The dripstone roof of the cave formed by the crystal depositions during millions of years, adds to the magical beauty of this place. El Farafra Oasis is a quiet and mystical desert, it is known as the White Desert.</string>
    <string name="abusimpletempledesc">
Abu Simbel is a historic site comprising two massive rock-cut temples in the village of Abu Simbel , Aswan Governorate, Upper Egypt, near the border with Sudan. It is situated on the western bank of Lake Nasser, about 230 km 140 mi southwest of Aswan (about 300 km (190 mi) by road). The complex is part of the UNESCO World Heritage Site known as the Nubian Monument which run from Abu Simbel downriver to Philae near Aswan, and include Amada, Wadi es Sebua, and other Nubian sites. The twin temples were originally carved out of the mountainside in the 13th century BC, during the 19th Dynasty reign of the Pharaoh Ramesses II. They serve as a lasting monument to the king Ramesses II. His wife Nefertari and children can be seen in smaller figures by his feet, considered to be of lesser importance and were not given the same position of scale. This commemorates his victory at the Battle of Kadesh. Their huge external rock relief figures have become iconic.
</string>
    <string name="karnaktempledesc">The Karnak Temple Complex, commonly known as Karnak  which was originally derived from Khurnaq fortified village 2, comprises a vast mix of decayed temples, pylons, chapels, and other buildings near Luxor, Egypt. Construction at the complex began during the reign of Senusret I reigned 1971–1926 BCE in the Middle Kingdom around 2000 1700 BCE and continued into the Ptolemaic Kingdom 305 30 BCE, although most of the extant buildings date from the New Kingdom. The area around Karnak was the ancient Egyptian Ipet isut The Most Selected of Places and the main place of worship of the 18th Dynastic Theban Triad, with the god Amun as its head. It is part of the monumental city of Thebes, and in 1979 it was inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List along with the rest of the city. The Karnak complex gives its name to the nearby, and partly surrounded, modern village of ElKarnak, 2.5 kilometres 1.6 miles north of Luxor.</string>
    <string name="templeofkalabshadesc">The Temple of Kalabsha also Temple of Mandulis is an ancient Egyptian temple that was originally located at Bab al-Kalabsha Gate of Kalabsha, approximately 50 km south of Aswan.1 The temple was inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 1979, along with other outstanding examples of Nubian architecture including Abu Simbel and Amada 2
The temple was situated on the west bank of the Nile River, in Nubia, and was originally built around 30 BC during the early Roman era. While the temple was constructed in Augustus reign, it was never finished. The temple was a tribute to Mandulis Merul, a Lower Nubian sun god. It was constructed over an earlier sanctuary of Amenhotep

</string>
    <string name="templeofkomobodesc">The Temple of Kom Ombo is an unusual double temple in the town of Kom Ombo in Aswan Governorate, Upper Egypt. It was constructed during the Ptolemaic dynasty, 180 47 BC Some additions to it were later made during the Roman period.
The building is unique because its double design meant that there were courts, halls, sanctuaries and rooms duplicated for two sets of gods. The southern half of the temple was dedicated to the crocodile god Sobek, god of fertility and creator of the world with Hathor and Khonsu. Meanwhile, the northern part of the temple was dedicated to the falcon god Haroeris Horus the Elder, along with Tasenetnofret the Good Sister, a special form of Hathor or Tefnet Tefnut and Panebtawy Lord of the Two Lands The temple is atypical because everything is perfectly symmetrical along the main axis.
</string>
    <string name="ramsesdesc">Temple of Ramses , site of two temples built by the Egyptian king Ramses II reigned 1279 13 bce,  southern Egypt. In ancient times the area was at the southern frontier of pharaonic Egypt, facing Nubia.
 the temples were salvaged from the rising waters of the Nile River caused by erection of the Aswan High Dam.
</string>
    <string name="sohaliislanddsec">The island of Suhail located in the south of Aswan Governorate is considered one of the places of tourism in Aswan, as it is the address of beauty and elegance when the beauty of charming nature meets with the mystery of the past surrounded by curiosity and passion, which attracts Egyptian lovers to discover more secrets that baffle the world until now, and is tempted to take memorial photos.</string>
    <string name="valentinislanddesc">Located in the centre of the River Nile and between the Cataract Islands opposite Aswan City,  sits the pretty relaxing Island of Lord Kitchener. Often a welcome excursion to many visitors wishing for a relaxing few hours in a green environment, cafe and Nile Views especially during the hotter months of the year.

Location:

A Felucca ride by local boat from the Corniche in Aswan and a 3 hour drive from Luxor City with an option to fly from Cairo to Aswan in about 1 hour.
</string>
    <string name="ajelicaislanddesc">Agilkia Island also called Agilika Arabic  is an island in the reservoir of the Old Aswan Dam along the Nile River in southern Egypt it is the present site of the relocated ancient Egyptian temple complex of Philae. Partially to completely flooded by the old dams construction in 1902, the Philae complex was dismantled and relocated to Agilkia island, as part of a wider UNESCO project related to the 1960s construction of the Aswan High Dam and the eventual flooding of many sites posed by its large reservoir upstream.
Agilkia, like the island, was the name chosen for the planned landing site on a comet by the Rosetta spacecraft missions Philae lander. Upon initial touchdown however, the lander took a large bounce followed by a smaller one before finally coming to rest perhaps a kilometre away from Agilkia, at a site named Abydos, after the ancient Egyptian city
</string>
    <string name="highdambridgedesc">The Aswan Dam, or more specifically since the 1960s, the Aswan High Dam, is the world largest embankment dam, which was built across the Nile in Aswan, Egypt, between 1960 and 1970. Its significance largely eclipsed the previous Aswan Low Dam initially completed in 1902 downstream. Based on the success of the Low Dam, then at its maximum utilization, construction of the High Dam became a key objective of the government following the Egyptian Revolution of 1952 with its ability to better control flooding, provide increased water storage for irrigation and generate hydroelectricity, the dam was seen as pivotal to Egypt planned industrialization. Like the earlier implementation, the High Dam has had a significant effect on the economy and culture of Egypt.</string>
    <string name="deirdesc">Deir el-Medina (Egyptian Arabic: دير المدينة), or Dayr al-Madīnah, is an ancient Egyptian workmens village which was home to the artisans who worked on the tombs in the Valley of the Kings during the 18th to 20th Dynasties of the New Kingdom of Egypt (ca. 1550–1080 BCE)[2] The settlements ancient name was Set maat (Place of Truth)and the workmen who lived there were called Servants in the Place of Truth.[3] During the Christian era, the temple of Hathor was converted into a church from which the Egyptian Arabic name Deir el-Medina (Monastery of the City) is derived.[4]
At the time when the world press was concentrating on Howard Carters discovery of the Tomb of Tutankhamun in 1922, a team led by Bernard Bruyère began to excavate the site.[5] This work has resulted in one of the most thoroughly documented accounts of community life in the ancient world that spans almost four hundred years. There is no comparable site in which the organisation, social interactions, working and living conditions of a community can be studied in such detail.[6]
</string>
    <string name="abydocitydesc">Abydos ˈbaɪdɒs (Arabic: أبيدوس, romanized: Abīdūs; Sahidic Coptic: Ⲉⲃⲱⲧ Ebōt) is one of the oldest cities of ancient Egypt, and also of the eighth nome in Upper Egypt. It is located about 11 kilometres (6.8 miles) west of the Nile at latitude 26° 10 N, near the modern Egyptian towns of El Araba El Madfuna and El Balyana. In the ancient Egyptian language, the city was called Abdju (bḏw or AbDw). The English name Abydos comes from the Greek, a name borrowed by Greek geographers from the unrelated city of Abydos on the Hellespont.
Considered one of the most important archaeological sites in Egypt, the sacred city of Abydos was the site of many ancient temples, including Umm el-Qaab, a royal necropolis where early pharaohs were entombed.[1] These tombs began to be seen as extremely significant burials and in later times it became desirable to be buried in the area, leading to the growth of the towns importance as a cult site.
</string>
    <string name="luxormusuemdesc">The Luxor Museum was inaugurated in 1975. It is a two-story building.The range of artifacts on display is far more restricted than the country main collections in the Egyptian Museum in Cairo this was, however, deliberate, since the museum prides itself on the quality of the pieces it has, the uncluttered way in which they are displayed, and the clear multilingual labeling used.
The museum was conceived by the Egyptian Ministry of Culture, which hired Dr. Mahmud El Hakim, a top Egyptian architect, to create the plans in 1962.[2] The installation of the museum art works came later and was finished between 1972 and 1975
</string>
    <string name="motuarydesc">The mortuary temple of Hatshepsut (Egyptian: Ḏsr-ḏsrw meaning "Holy of Holies") is a mortuary temple built during the reign of Pharaoh Hatshepsut of the Eighteenth Dynasty of Egypt.[b] Located opposite the city of Luxor, it is considered to be a masterpiece of ancient architecture.[c] Its three massive terraces rise above the desert floor and into the cliffs of Deir el-Bahari. Her tomb, KV20, lies inside the same massif capped by El Qurn, a pyramid for her mortuary complex. At the edge of the desert, 1 km (0.62 mi) east, connected to the complex by a causeway lies the accompanying valley temple. Across the river Nile, the whole structure points towards the monumental Eighth Pylon, Hatshepsu most recognizable addition to the Temple of Karnak and the site from which the procession of the Beautiful Festival of the Valley departed. The temple twin functions are identified by its axes: its main east-west axis served to receive the barque of Amun-Re at the climax of the festival, while its north-south axis represented the life cycle of the pharaoh from coronation to rebirth</string>
    <string name="ndalanddesc">It opened in April 2012, many, many issues and problems were discovered upon our first visit, some of which are still there today, almost one year on.

This page has been created to share the journey, of some of these animals that have survived, or have not been returned to the original supplier in Cairo.

Basic things, such as lack of knowledge, understanding and care, have resulted in many animals dying. Those that remain are  unhappy and malnourished.

El Nada Land has started to build new enclosures for some of the animals, but it is a slow process and the animals are being neglected ie Food, cleaning the current inappropriate enclosures and water- The basic essentials for life.

I care about all of the animals, but in particular, I have gained a respect and love, for Robbie, the Patas monkey, that lives
alone. Despite her horrid life, she is the most dignified lady and the main attraction of this place.

I visit weekly, sometimes more, but every time I visit, I struggle emotionally, it breaks my heart, to see animals so unhappy.
At this stage of the rebuilding, the current animal organisations that exist in Egypt, should be working with El Nada Land, to ensure all is correct and built to a standard, thus providing the very best for these poor creatures.
The owner is willing to co operate and needs help, support and advice, as well as the staff that Look after Robbie and her friends.
</string>
    <string name="bananaislanddesc">Discover this unique and unusual Banana Island Tour in Luxor to enjoy our Egypt Day Tours to the Banana Island (Gezira el-Mozh), placed along the Nile valley, and draws visitors from all over the world with its famous activity, banana plantation. You will get to learn about how bananas are being conserved and planted, as well as the important care given to their maturity. then take your time to relax in the outdoor cafe to test some yummy foods and drinks. Or take your picnic to experience in the outdoor setting.</string>
    <string name="vallyofkingdesc">The Valley of the Kings (Arabic: وادي الملوك Wādī al-Mulūk; Coptic: ϫⲏⲙⲉ, romanized: džēme[1] Late Coptic: [ˈʃɪ.mæ]), also known as the Valley of the Gates of the Kings (Arabic: وادي أبواب الملوك Wādī Abwāb al-Mulūk),[2] is a valley in Egypt where, for a period of nearly 500 years from the 16th to 11th century BC, rock-cut tombs were excavated for the pharaohs and powerful nobles of the New Kingdom (the Eighteenth to the Twentieth Dynasties of Ancient Egypt).[3][4]
The valley stands on the west bank of the Nile opposite Thebes (modern Luxor), within the heart of the Theban Necropolis.[5] The wadi consists of two valleys: the East Valley (where the majority of the royal tombs are situated) and the West Valley (Valley of the Monkeys).[6][7]
</string>
    <string name="vallyofqueendesc">The Valley of the Queens (Arabic: وادي الملكات Wādī al Malekāt) is a site in Egypt, where the wives of pharaohs were buried in ancient times. It was known then as Ta-Set-Neferu, meaning "the place of beauty". It was most famous for being the burial site of many wives of Pharaohs.[1] Pharaohs themselves were buried in the Valley of the Kings.[2]
Using the limits described by Christian Leblanc, the Valley of the Queens consists of the main wadi, which contains most of the tombs, along with the Valley of Prince Ahmose, the Valley of the Rope, the Valley of the Three Pits, and the Valley of the Dolmen. The main wadi contains 91 tombs and the subsidiary valleys add another 19 tombs. The burials in the subsidiary valleys all date to the 18th Dynasty.[3]
The reason for choosing the Valley of the Queens as a burial site is not known. The close proximity to the workers village of Deir el-Medina and the Valley of the Kings may have been a factor. Another consideration could have been the existence of a sacred grotto dedicated to Hathor at the entrance of the Valley. This grotto may have been associated with rejuvenation of the dead.[3]
</string>
    <string name="ramsuemdesc">The Ramesseum is the memorial temple (or mortuary temple) of Pharaoh Ramesses II ("Ramesses the Great", also spelled "Ramses" and "Rameses"). It is located in the Theban Necropolis in Upper Egypt, on the west of the River Nile, across from the modern city of Luxor. The name – or at least its French form Rhamesséion – was coined by Jean-François Champollion, who visited the ruins of the site in 1829 and first identified </string>
    <string name="intergardendesc">The International Garden is a public park on Abbas El Akkad Street in Nasr City, Cairo. It is called "international" because each country has a part of the park, where its most famous trees and animals and the most prominent features of it are located. There is a special section for the UAE, another for Saudi Arabia and Bahrain, another for Japan, and for all Arab or foreign countries. It is heavily subsidized by the Egyptian government and even makes its entry fee low for all to enjoy.</string>
    <string name="cournishdesc">The Nile Corniche is a global walkway in the city of Luxor, with its unique archaeological character, and it constitutes a masterpiece on the Luxor Nile, as it embraces the fragrant history and the famous Luxor temples. Egyptians and foreigners after turning it into a tourist attraction and a unique outlet for the people of Luxor.

</string>
    <string name="luxortempledesc">The Luxor Temple (Arabic: معبد الأقصر) is a large Ancient Egyptian temple complex located on the east bank of the Nile River in the city today known as Luxor (ancient Thebes) and was constructed approximately 1400 BCE. In the Egyptian language it was known as ipet resyt, "the southern sanctuary". It was one of the two primary temples on the east bank, the other being Karnak.[1] Unlike the other temples in Thebes, Luxor temple is not dedicated to a cult god or a deified version of the pharaoh in death. Instead, Luxor temple is dedicated to the rejuvenation of kingship; it may have been where many of the pharaohs of Egypt were crowned in reality or conceptually (as in the case of Alexander the Great, who claimed he was crowned at Luxor but may never have traveled south of Memphis, near modern Cairo).</string>
    <string name="pyrmids">Pyrmids</string>
    <string name="solarboat">"Solar boat "</string>
    <string name="pharonic">Pharonic village</string>
    <string name="alazhermosque">Alazher mosque</string>
    <string name="alorman">Alorman Park</string>
    <string name="thegrand">The grand eg musuem</string>
    <string name="pyrmidsdesc">The Egyptian pyramids are ancient masonry structures located in Egypt. Sources cite at least 118 identified "Egyptian" pyramids
        .[1][2] Approximately 80 pyramids were built within the Kingdom of Kush, now located in the modern country of Sudan.
        Of those located in modern Egypt, most were built as tombs for the country pharaohs and their consorts during the Old and Middle Kingdom periods.[3][4][5]

The earliest known Egyptian pyramids are found at Saqqara, northwest of Memphis,
        although at least one step-pyramid-like structure has been found at Saqqara,
        dating to the First Dynasty Mastaba 3808, which has been attributed to the reign of Pharaoh Anedjib,
        with inscriptions, and other archaeological remains of the period, suggesting there may have been others.


The most famous Egyptian pyramids are those found at Giza, on the outskirts of Cairo.
        Several of the Giza pyramids are counted among the largest structures ever built.

       </string>
    <string name="solarboatdesc">The Giza Solar boat museum is located in Egypt. It was constructed around 1985 and was dedicated to display the reconstructed Khufu ship, a solar barque this however was relocated to the Grand Egyptian Museum in August 2021.[1]
    The museum lies just a few meters from where it was found on the southern side of the pyramid.[3] It was constructed next to the Great Pyramid of Khufu. The museum was equipped with modern techniques and technologies in order to preserve the solar boat. The museum was constructed so as to enable viewing the boat from three different levels in three floors.
        On the ground floor, one could view the bottom of the boat.</string>
    <string name="pharonicdesc">The village covers 490,000 square feet at Ya aqoub Island . It is surrounded by 5000 trees tall enough to screen adjacent vestiges of modern life, making a visitor feel as if gone back 5000 years in history .

The idea of this village occurred to Dr. Hassan Ragab 20 years ago, when he first came to Ya aqoob Island to grow papyrus necessary for paper fabrication, an art which he brought back to life after it had disappeared for l000 years.

The pharaonic village represent industries, games, arts and moments from history and legend. There are also services such as cafeterias, boat rentals, a childrens playground and a restaurant that serves both Egyptian and European dishes which help to make your stay even more enjoyable.</string>
    <string name="alazherdesc">Al-Azhar Park (Arabic: حديقة الأزهر) is a public park located in Cairo, Egypt.

Among several honors, this park is listed as one of the world is sixty great public spaces by the Project for Public Spaces.[1] The park was created by the Historic Cities Support Programme of the Aga Khan Trust for Culture, an entity of the Aga Khan Development Network. The park was developed at a cost in excess of USD $30 million, its funding a gift to Cairo from Aga Khan IV, a descendant of the Fatimid Caliphs of Cairo.</string>
    <string name="alazhermosquedesc">While there are hundreds of old mosques to visit in Cairo, there is none that can compete with Al-Azhar Mosque in standing and importance to the history of Islam. Founded by the Fatimids in 970 AD as a mosque dedicated to both worship and learning, it developed over the centuries into the most important center of Islamic theology and learning in the world.



Over a thousand years since its founding, Al-Azhar Mosque and the university that bears its name draw students from all over the world to learn about the history of Islam and the different schools of thought that govern the interpretation of the Koran.



From its founding, Al-Azhar University was an institution that revealed in pluralism. Founded by the Ismaili Shii Fatimid Dynasty, it became a Sunni university under subsequent dynasties in Egypt, but, in spite tension between these different theologies, Sunni and Shii scholars have worked, taught, and debated alongside one another at Al-Azhar for most of its history.
         .</string>
    <string name="alormandec">Al Orman Park lies in the district of Doqqui, in the city of Giza, near the Zoo and the Cairo University. The park, a large green space once part of the gardens of the Khedive Ismail is palace, was designed as a botanical garden with 100,000 kinds of rare plants. It hosts a spring flower show that started in 1920 and soon developed from a one-day event on the first day of the spring season into a weekly event with a competition offering a prize for the best flowers on show.</string>
    <string name="thezoodesc">The zoo, this can be the oldest and oldest park, which was one in all the foremost important huge parks in Africa and therefore the Middle East, and per chronological monitoring, it is the third zoo within the world, and therefore the first in Africa, that park was a natural product of the Egyptian historical relationship with pets and wild animals. and therefore the plane, which came to observe us how Queen Cleopatra and therefore the ancient kings of the Pharaohs wont to like to collect animals during their trips in Africa to display them in their palaces, and although the quantity of its visitors exceeds 1,000,000 visitors annually, most Egyptians do not bring it to mind except on holidays and occasions.</string>
    <string name="thegrandegmusuemdesc">The GEM is built on a slope and straddles the 162 foot difference in levels between the Nile valley, where you enter, and the Giza plateau, where the main galleries are situated. There are sculpture gardens in the museum park, while a massive statue of Ramses II greets you upon entry into the main atrium. From here, the Grand Staircase, which leads from valley level to plateau, will be lined with 87 statues of kings and gods.</string>

    <string name="sphinxdesc">The Great Sphinx is among the worlds largest sculptures, measuring some 240 feet (73 metres) long and 66 feet (20 metres) high. It features a lions body and a human head adorned with a royal headdress. The statue was carved from a single piece of limestone, and pigment residue suggests that the entire Great Sphinx was painted. According to some estimates, it would have taken about three years for 100 workers, using stone hammers and copper chisels, to finish the statue.</string>
    <string name="citbeydesc">The Citadel of Qaitbay (or the Fort of Qaitbay; Arabic: قلعة قايتباي) is a 15th-century defensive fortress located on the Mediterranean sea coast, in Alexandria, Egypt. It was built from 1477 to 1479 AD (882–884 AH) by Sultan Al-Ashraf Sayf al-Din Qait Bay.[2] The Citadel is situated on the eastern side of the northern tip of Pharos Island at the mouth of the Eastern Harbour.[3]
The Qaitbay Citadel in Alexandria is considered one of the most important defensive strongholds, not only in Egypt, but also along the Mediterranean Sea coast. It formulated an important part of the fortification system of Alexandria in the 15th century AD.
</string>
    <string name="abuqirdesc">Abu Qir (Arabic: ابو قير, Abu Qīr, [æbu] or [æbo ʔiːɾ], Coptic: ⲁⲡⲁⲕⲩⲣⲓ Apakyri), formerly also spelled Abukir or Aboukir,[1] is a town on the Mediterranean coast of Egypt, near the ruins of ancient Canopus and 23 kilometers (14 mi) northeast of Alexandria by rail. It is located on Abu Qir Peninsula, with Abu Qir Bay to the east.
The town present name is Arabic for "Father Cyrus", one of a pair of fourth century Christian martyrs venerated as Saints Cyrus and John by the Coptic Church.
The remains of many ancient buildings from the Egyptian, Greek and Roman periods can be found near the town. About 3 kilometers (2 mi) southeast of the town are the ruins of the Ancient Egyptian coastal town of Canopus. A little farther east, the now-dry Canopic branch of the Nile once entered the Mediterranean.
</string>
    <string name="abasmosquedesc">The Abu al-Abbas al-Mursi Mosque (Arabic: جامع أبو العباس المرسي) is an Egyptian mosque in the city of Alexandria. It is dedicated to the 13th century Murcian Andalusi Sufi saint Abul Abbas al-Mursi, whose tomb it contains.
It is located in the Anfoushi neighborhood of Alexandria, near the Citadel of Qaitbay.
Abul Abbas al-Mursi died in 1286 and was buried here. The mosque was first built in 1307.
The mosque was designed and built in today current form by Eugenio Valzania and Mario Rossi in the years 1929/1945, and was highly influenced by Egypt Old Cairo buildings and architecture.
It served in turn as a key source of inspiration for the much larger Sheikh Zayed Mosque in Abu Dhabi, completed in 2007 after more than a decade of building work.
</string>
    <string name="boltcastledesc">Boldt Castle, located near Alexandria Bay, NY in the famed 1000 Islands is once again becoming what it was always meant to be,
        the premier home and attraction in the region. Whether you are making an annual visit to see what is new, looking for an affordable family vacation close to home or a couple seeking that romantic getaway, Boldt Castle and the Boldt Yacht House has something for you! In fact, the Castles legendary beauty nestled among the St Lawrence Rivers 1000 Islands will keep you returning year after year</string>
    <string name="lostcitydesc">Legend of Appearing a few rare inscriptions and ancient texts, the city of Thonis-Heracleion was hidden away for thousands of years, submerged deep under the sea.
After searching for years by screening the vast area of the Abu Qir Bay off the coast of Egypt, French archaeologist Franck Goddio and his team saw a colossal face emerge from the watery shadows</string>
    <string name="komeldikadesc">Kom El Deka (Arabic: كوم الدكة), also known as Kom el-Dikka,
        is a neighborhood and archaeological site in Alexandria
        , Egypt.[1] Early Kom El-Dikka was a well-off residential area,
        and later it was a major civic center in Alexandria, with a bath complex (thermae), auditoria (lecture halls),
        and a theatre.[2] Today, Kom el-Dikka is the largest and most complete above ground archeological site in Alexandria.
        It provides large amounts of archeological evidence of urban life in Roman Egypt, including early villas and their mosaics, and late Roman public works.</string>
    <string name="raseltindesc">Ras El Tin Palace (Arabic: قصر رأس التين Qaṣr Ras Al Tīn, literally, "Cape Fig Palace")
        is a palace on the coast of the Mediterranean Sea in Alexandria, Egypt. It is one of the official residences for
        a serving President of Egypt. Under the Muhammad Ali Dynasty of Egypt and Sudan, it was a royal palace. Ras El Tin
        Palace is the oldest royal Egyptian palace still in use. The palace is located in the Ras el-Tin quarter of Alexandria
        overlooking the city Western Harbour.[1] It was built on a promontory which in antiquity had been the site of the island of Pharos.</string>
    <string name="alexlibrarydesc">The Bibliotheca Alexandrina (Latin[1] for "Library of Alexandria"; Egyptian Arabic: مكتبة الإسكندرية Maktabet al-Eskendereyya,
        Egyptian Arabic: [mæk tæb(e)t eskendeˈɾejjæ]) is a major library and cultural center on the shore of the Mediterranean Sea in the Egyptian city of Alexandria.
        It is a commemoration of the Library of Alexandria, once one of the largest libraries worldwide, which was lost in antiquity. The idea of reviving the old library
        dates back to 1974, when a committee set up by Alexandria University selected a plot of land for its new library. Construction work began in 1995 and, after some
        US$220 million had been spent, the complex was officially inaugurated on 16 October 2002. In 2010, the library received a donation of 500,000 books from the Bibliothèque
        nationale de France (BnF). The gift makes the Bibliotheca Alexandrina the sixth-largest Francophone library in the world.</string>
    <string name="stanelydesc">Stanley (Arabic: ستانلي) is a neighborhood near the city centre of Alexandria.
        The area is most famous for the iconic Stanley Bridge on the Corniche, as well as its private-access beach.
        The bridge has a total length of 400 meters with 6 spans . It is the first bridge in Egypt to be constructed into the sea
        , with total length of 400 m. Considered of 6 spans , It constitute amajor part of the reconstruction and decoration of Alexandria cornich . </string>
    <string name="montazhdesc">Montaza Palace (Arabic: قصر المنتزه) is a palace, museum and extensive gardens in the Montaza district of Alexandria, Egypt. It was built on a low plateau east of central Alexandria overlooking a beach on the Mediterranean Sea.
The extensive Montaza Palace grounds first had the Salamlek Palace, built in 1892 by Khedive Abbas II, the last Muhammad Ali Dynasty ruler to hold the Khedive title over the Khedivate of Egypt and Sudan. It was used as a hunting lodge and residence for his companion.
</string>
    <string name="aielgardendesc">The Snake Park in Dahab is one of the amazing areas that have been discovered recently, and it is one of the most terrifying and beautiful areas at the same time for diving enthusiasts, and this is because this park is all under the water. We will know him now.</string>
    <string name="nabqreservedesc">Nabq Reserve was declared a nature reserve in 1992, with an area of 600 km2 (of which 440 km2 is on dry land in addition to 130 km2 in the water range). The reserve is 35 km north of Sharm El Sheikh. In late 2010, the reserve was used as a safe beach for tourists to practice swimming after the famous shark attack on the beaches of Sharm El-Sheihk . </string>
    <string name="wadignaidesc">Wadi Gnai is a little oasis and one could say that it is located directly behind the Sunsplash Divers Resort backdoor.
Hike through this calming landscape, into the palm grove and the abandoned gardens of the Bedouins. As there is water in Wadi Gnai it is always lush and green – and in the rare event of rain you will be able to find many different types of desert flowers in full bloom.


</string>
    <string name="coloredcanyonsdesc">the Colored Canyon might confuse your eyes with such a spectacular view.
Hidden in the desert in an area called the Sinai Peninsula, the Colored Canyon is one of those best-kept secrets of the marvelous country of the Great Pyramids.
Located at 210 miles from the big city of Cairo, the Colored Canyon is found in the area of the Sinai. The Colored Canyon is 800 meters long and has a depth of 30 meters.

Nuweiba, a very laid back and a small village in Egypt, is the closest town to the Colored Canyon.
</string>
    <string name="blueholedesc">The Blue Hole is a diving location on the southeast Sinai, a few kilometres north of Dahab, Egypt on the coast of the Red Sea.
The Blue Hole is a submarine sinkhole, with a maximum depth within the hole of just over 100 m (328 feet). There is a shallow opening to the sea around 6 m (20 feet) deep, known as "the saddle", and a 26 m (85 feet) long tunnel, known as "the Arch", whose ceiling is at a depth of 55 m (181 feet) and whose bottom falls away as it reaches the seaward side to about 120 m (394 feet).[1] On the seaward side the floor drops steeply to over 1,000 metres (3,300 ft).[2] The hole and the surrounding area have an abundance of coral and reef fish.[2] The Blue Hole is popular for freediving because of the depth directly accessible from shore and the lack of curre
</string>
    <string name="lighthousedesc">The Lighthouse is a very popular dive site in Dahab; it is perfect for teaching all levels, from open water to technical. As the Lighthouse is a site which has one of the easiest entries and exits and it is always sheltered from the wind, diving here is always possible. As you step in the water you will find a shallow sandy area that slowly drops off into a large grassy slope. Look out for seahorses and pegasus seamoths that generally occur in pairs. There is also a good chance to find the rare anglerfish.</string>
    <string name="canyondesc">The Dahab Canyon is the classic canyon, an essential dive for all fanatics of caves and cavern diving. The Canyon is itself quite a phenomenon. Up to 10 meters high and virtually closed over at the top, it snakes its way up from the depths, to emerge in a large glassfish filled coral dome. The Canyon dive site offers an easy entry and exit point through a shallow, sandy lagoon. This leads out to beautiful coral gardens inhabited by Butterflyfishes, Unicornfishes, Octopus, Pufferfish and of course Red Sea Anthias, which can only be fully explored after several visits. The Canyon itself is positioned about five minutes north-east from the exit of the lagoon. The entry to the Canyon is done through it largest point at about 20 meters. The progression through the Canyon is easy and the light effect caused by the sun rays is fantastic.</string>
    <string name="lagonislanddesc">A serene haven of beauty  comfort. A place to unwind, chill  relax. Very safe for kids as well. extremely romantic for couples. A hub for kite surfers, divers, and snorkeling activities. Food  beverage retail is available complemented with toilets facility. A must destination if you are visiting Dahab.
 It is very beautiful beach (closed lagoon) with crystal color water, and no rocks, and no corals. It is perfect for professional kite surf. There are very limited poor services there (only shadow, Bedouin tea, or soft drink) and no Egyptian signal at all, and no fresh water shower. To go there, you have to ride a car to blue hole, then a boat to Abu Galoom, then a vehicle to blue lagoon.
</string>
    <string name="thrushtreedesc">At low tide, Qulaan reveals four sandy, golden islands, with a touch of green mangrove trees growing out of the sea.

Located in the south of Egypt, in the protected area of the National Park of Wadi El Gemal, 170 Kms from Port Ghalib. These sights are not a work of fiction but a reality more beautiful than what a writer can describe or a photographer can capture.

Qulaan Islands stretch over a bay that is divided into four pieces of land with mangrove trees all around. This setting creates a sustainable eco-system for the wildlife under the sea and the birds that come to feed.</string>
    <string name="meteorlakedesc">It is a natural pool, made of a unique rock formation, which is believed by the area inhabitants to have been shaped by a meteorite, hitting the coast, located 8 kms south Marsa Alam, 20 minutes from Port Ghalib. The pool, several meters in diameter, is shaped like an eye filled with the turquoise blue waters of the Red Sea. The pool is around 8-10 meters depth.</string>
    <string name="abughOsounwreckdesc">The wreck has attracted many types of coral and marine life including Napoleons, Lionfish, Parrotfish, Surgeon fish, Butterflyfish and Moray eel. Suitable for all diving levels providing suitable precautions taken and a guide present. Nudibranch, lionfish, lionfish, sweet lip, bannerfish, butterfly fish, Spanish dancer (night), crocodile fish, sweeper, Mediterranean moray or roman eel, ray. </string>
    <string name="portghalidesc">Port Ghalib is located in Marsa Alam along the Southern Red Sea Coral Coast of Egypt, 67 kms south of Quseir City. It is an international destination, a premier integrated resort community of distinction, activity and variety; setting it apart from other resort communities in the region.</string>
    <string name="berenicevillagedesc">Baranis, is an ancient seaport of Egypt on the western shore of the Red Sea. It is situated about 825 km south of Suez, 260 km east of Aswan in Upper Egypt and 140 km south of Marsa Alam.[2] It was founded in 275 BCE by Ptolemy II Philadelphus (285–246 BCE), who named it after his mother, Berenice I of Egypt.[3]

A high mountain range runs along the African coast and separates the Nile Valley from the Red Sea; Berenice was sited upon a narrow rim of shore between the mountains and the Red Sea, at the head of the Sinus Immundus,[4] a south-facing bay sheltered on the north by a high peninsula then called Lepte Extrema, and to the south by a chain of small islands scattered across the mouth of the bay</string>
    <string name="alsamadayreservedesc">The Samadai reef area, located in Marsa Alam, is shaped like a horseshoe, and is characterized by various coral reefs.



This area was declared almost 21 years ago as a nature reserve for encompassing the largest gathering of spinner dolphins, coming in the third rank after the Hawaiian Islands in the first position, followed by Brazil in the second.</string>
    <string name="wadielgemalreservedesc">Wadi El Gemal National Park is a national park in Egypt. It is 7,450 square kilometres (2,880 sq mi) in size, including 4,770 square kilometres (1,840 sq mi) of land and 2,100 square kilometres (810 sq mi) of marine space.[1]

The coastal area features coral reefs with 450 species of coral and over 1200 species of fish. Approximately 17% of the marine life is native to the Red Sea.[2] It also includes five islands, including Wadi El Gemal Island</string>
    <string name="dolphinhousedesc">The dolphin house Sataya Reef is the best snorkeling destination in the red sea. It will take two hours by boat to the south heading to the Sataya national park area, which is the most famous area as the home of dolphins, It is possible to see a large number of different types of dolphins: The most famous ones are the spinner dolphins, which are active and dynamic, The Sataya region has a large surface and is surrounded by coral reefs on three sides

Read more about Sataya Dolphin House Snorkel Trip - Marsa Alam </string>
    <string name="leadmountaindesc">Lead Mountain is located on private land, but can be hiked by the public. The primary route to Lead Mountain begins just north of the at the gated end of a dirt road southeast of the peak.[5] The route follows the dirt road beyond the gate before turning up a path that ascends southeast of the summit before continuing up the east side of the mountain to reach the summit.

On a clear day views from the summit stretch to the south to Acadia National Park and the Gulf of Maine. There are two communication towers on the summit. South of the mountain is the small Bear Pond, while the much larger Upper Lead Mountain Pond is west of the mountain.</string>
    <string name="alshabamosquedesc">The mosque is a very good representation of Islamic architecture in the new Era.  It attracts of all those who enter Sharm el-Sheikh city.

 The mosque overlooking the sea at the entrance to the city of Sharm el-Sheikh. The mosque is built on an area of 3,000 square meters, with two 76-meter-long minarets. The roof of mosque rises 36 meters high. It can hold up to 3,000 worshippers. It has thirty-six bathrooms. It has two Mazatlán for praying .It also boasts a service area and a library with books in several languages. This is beside the service buildings and commercial units operating endowment of the mosque, to become the second largest mosque in the city after the Mustafa mosque.</string>

    <string name="coloredcanyondesc">A visit to the canyon provides instant recognition of where it gets its name. The walls of the canyon, which reach up to sixteen stories, are easily the most colorful and intriguing rock formations in all of Sinai. They were created by the erosion of water upon sandstone and limestone. In some places, the deep coloration of rocks gives the canyon walls a prismatic and metallic sheen; in others, the stone is so smooth that it appears soft and billowy.</string>
    <string name="peaceicondesc">the peace icon memorial in Sharm El Sheikh said that it is not just a memorial that the all world celebrated with during the economic conference event in the city, but it is a real icon for peace have been designed in a technical uniquely way that combines modernity with the Pharaonic civilization, as a direct message for the whole world that Egypt is the land of peace and the city of Sharm El Sheikh is the icon of peace, pointing out that the real surprise is recording this monument in the Guinness book of records as the largest and longest metal art work in the world.</string>
    <string name="sohosunsetdesc">SOHO Square Sharm El Sheikh is the middle East leading shopping entertainment center, the finest in the Red Sea region. SOHO Square is a hub for entertainment, dining, clubbing, shopping, sport activities enhance with a dancing fountain, mega stage  kids fun activities</string>
    <string name="mountcatrindesc">Although Saint Catherine was not established as a city at that time, it was always part of the Egyptian Empire throughout history and it was part of the province of "Deshret Reithu".

In the 16th century BC, the Egyptian pharaohs built the way of Shur across Sinai to Beersheba and on to Jerusalem. The region provided the Egyptian Empire with turquoise, gold, and copper, and well-preserved ruins of mines and temples are found not far from Saint Catherine at Serabit el-Khadim and Wadi Mukattab, the Valley of Inscription. They include temples from the 12th Dynasty, dedicated to Hathor, goddess of love, music, and beauty, and from the New Kingdom dedicated to Sopdu, the god of the Eastern Desert.</string>
    <string name="dolphinparkdesc">Dolphina Park is located at Nabq Bay. Tickets to the park can be booked directly or as part of an organized day trip.Although Viator tours do not include this activity, dolphin swims, trainer experiences, and diving sessions are available for purchase at the park for additional fees starting at $25.</string>
    <string name="rasmohameddesc">It has stunning views across the Red Sea which gave the area huge strategic importance throughout history. Today, it is a beautiful National Park, set up to protect marine and land wildlife and maintain the natural beauty of the area. Not far south of the resort town of Sharm el –Sheikh, this protected area is a must-see for visitors interested in the vast array of natural beauty found in and around the Red Sea. With the building of any kind prohibited, Ras Mohammed remains a timeless and pristine environment in which nature flourishes.</string>
    <string name="safridesc">A fantastic chance to experience real Bedouin life. Ride a camel, enjoy a quad safari, watch the beautiful sunset over the Sinai desert, drink and eat authentic Bedouin food, watch a great show of belly dancing, fire-breathing and more.

Then stand back and watch the spectacular view of the milky way and stars through a telescope before getting back on your quad or buggy for a final safari through the desert.This trip runs every day.Upon arrival you will take part in a 45 minute quad safari to the bedouin camp then enjoy a 15 minute camel ride.  </string>
    <string name="ghazalagardendesc">Just a five minute stroll from the centre of Naama Bay and five minutes to the beach it shares with The Ghazala Beach Hotel, the Ghazala Gardens offers a perfect balance of scale and facilities. The delightful gardens teem with exotic plants and a lagoon pool that give it a truly tropical feel. You can even swim right from your terrace with our poolside rooms! There are some delicious dining options, including one of Egypt few Brazilian restaurants.</string>
</resources>